recording all librivox recordings are in the public domain for more information
or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by J Hall
the Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum Chapter 8 The Deadly Poppy Field
Our little party of travelers awakened the next morning refreshed and full of
hope, and Dorothy breakfast like a princess off peaches and plums from the
trees beside the river. Behind them was the dark forest they had passed safely
through, although they had suffered many discouragements; but before them was a
lovely, sunny country that seemed to beckon them on to the Emerald City. To be
sure, the broad river now cut them off from this beautiful land. But the raft
was nearly done, and after the Tin Woodman had cut a few more logs and
fastened them together with wooden pens they were ready to start.
Dorothy sat down in the middle of the raft and held Toto in her arms. When the
Cowardly Lion stepped upon the raft it tipped badly, for he was big and heavy;
but the Scarecrow and the Tin Woodman stood upon the other end to steady it,
and they had long poles in their hands to push the raft through the water. They
got along quite well at first, but when they reached the middle of the river the
swift current swept the raft downstream, farther and farther away from the road
of yellow brick. And the water grew so deep that the long poles would not touch
the bottom. “This is bad,” said the Tin Woodman, “for if we cannot get to the land
we shall be carried into the country of the Wicked Witch of the West, and she
will enchant us and make us her slaves.” “And then I should get no brains,” said the
Scarecrow. “And I should get no courage,” said the Cowardly Lion. “And I should get
no heart,” said the Tin Woodman. “And I should never get back to Kansas,” said
Dorothy. “We must certainly get to the Emerald City if we can,” the Scarecrow
continued, and he pushed so hard on his long pole that it stuck fast and the mud
at the bottom of the river. Then, before he could pull it out again— —or let go— —the
raft was swept away in the porch crow left clinging to the pole in the
middle of the river goodbye he called after them, and they were very sorry to leave him.
Indeed, the Tin Woodman began to cry, but fortunately remembered that he might
rust so dried his tears on Dorothy’s apron. Of course this was a bad thing for
the Scarecrow. “I am now worse off than when I first met Dorothy,” he thought. “Then,
I was stuck to a pole in them in a cornfield, where I could make believe
scare the crows, at any rate. But surely there is no use for a Scarecrow stuck on
a pole in the middle of a river. I am afraid I shall never have any brains,
after all!” Down the stream the raft floated, and the poor Scarecrow was left
far behind. Then the Lion said: “Something must be done to save us. I think I can
swim to the shore and pull the raft after me, if you will only hold fast to
the tip of my tail.” So we sprang into the water, and the Tin Woodman caught fast
hold of his tail.
Then the Lion began to swim with all his might toward the shore. It was hard work,
although he was big; but by and by they were drawn out of the current, and then
Dorothy took the Tin Woodman’s long pole and helped push the raft to the land.
They were all tired out when they reached the shore at last and stepped
off upon the pretty green grass, and they also knew that the stream had carried
them a long way past the road of yellow brick that led to the Emerald City. “What
shall we do now?” asked the Tin Woodman, as the Lion lay down on the grass to let
the sun dry him. “We must get back to the road, in some way,” said Dorothy. “The best
plan will be to walk along the riverbank until we come to the road again,” remarked
the Lion. So, when they were rested, Dorothy picked up her basket and they
started along the grassy bank, to the road from which the river had carried
them. It was a lovely country, with plenty of flowers and fruit trees and sunshine
to cheer them, and had they not felt so sorry for the poor Scarecrow, they could
have been very happy. They walked along as fast as they could,
Dorothy only stopping once to pick a beautiful flower; and after a
the Ted woman cried out: “Look!” Then they all looked at the river and saw the
Scarecrow perched upon his pole in the middle of the water, looking very lonely
and sad. “What can we do to save him?” asked Dorothy. The line in the Woodman both
shook their heads, for they did not know.
So they sat down upon the bank and gazed wistfully at the Scarecrow until a Stork
flew by, who, upon seeing them, stopped to rest at the water’s edge. “Who are you and
where are you going?” asked the Stork. “I am Dorothy,” answered the girl, “and these are
my friends, the Tin Woodman and the Cowardly Lion; and we are going to the
Emerald City.” “This isn’t the road,” said the Stork, as she twisted her long neck
and looked sharply at the queer party. “I know it,” returned Dorothy, “but we have
lost the Scarecrow, and are wondering how we shall get him again.” “Where is he?” asked
the Stork. “Over there in the river,” answered the little girl. “If he wasn’t so
big and heavy I would get him for you,” remarked the Stork. “He isn’t heavy a bit,”
said Dorothy eagerly, “for he is stuffed with straw; and if you will bring him
back to us, we shall thank you ever and ever so much.” “Well I will try,” said the
Stork, “but if I find he is too heavy to
carry I shall have to drop him in the river again.” So the big bird flew into
the air and over the water till she came to where the Scarecrow was perched upon
his pole. Then the Stork with her great claws grabbed the Scarecrow by the arm
and carried him up into the air and back to the bank, where Dorothy and the Lion
and the Tin Woodman and Toto were sitting. When the Scarecrow
found himself among his friends again, he was so happy that he hugged them all,
even the Lion in Toto; and as they walked along he sang told to re-do at every
step, he felt so gay. “I was afraid I should have to stay in the river forever,”
he said, “but that kind Stork saved me, and if I ever get any brains I shall find
the Stork again and do her some kindness in return.” “That’s all right,” said the
Stork, who was flying along beside them. “I always like to help anyone in trouble.
But I must go now, for my babies are waiting in the nest for me. I hope you
will find the Emerald City and that Oz will help you.” “Thank you,” replied Dorothy,
and then the kind Stork flew into the air and was soon out of sight. They
walked along listening to the singing of the brightly colored birds and looking
at the lovely flowers which now became so thick that the ground was carpeted
with them. There were big yellow and white and blue and purple blossoms
beside great clusters of scarlet poppies, which were so brilliant in color they
almost dazzled Dorothy’s eyes. “Aren’t they beautiful?” the girl asked, as she
breathed in the spicy scent of the bright flowers. “I suppose so,”
answered the Scarecrow. “When I have brains, I shall probably like them better.”
“If I only had a heart, I should love them,” added the Tin Woodman. “I always did like
flowers,” said the Lion.
“They have seemed so helpless and frail.
But there are none in the forest so bright as these.” They now came upon more
and more of the big scarlet poppies, and fewer and fewer of the other flowers; and
soon they found themselves in the midst of a great meadow of poppies. Now it is
well known that when there are many of these flowers together their odour is so
powerful that anyone who breathes it falls asleep, and if the sleeper is not
carried away from the scent of the flowers, he sleeps on and on forever. But
Dorothy did not know this, nor could she get away from the bright red flowers
that were everywhere about; so presently her eyes grew heavy and she felt she
must sit down to rest and to sleep. But the Tin Woodman would not let her do
this. “We must hurry and get back to the road of yellow brick before dark,” he said;
and the Scarecrow agreed with him. So they kept walking until Dorothy could
stand no longer. Her eyes closed in spite of herself and she forgot where she was
and fell among the poppies, fast asleep.
“What shall we do?” asked the Tin Woodman.
“If we leave her he or she will die,” said the Lion. “The smell of the flowers is
killing us all. I myself can scarcely keep my eyes open at all
and the dog is asleep already.” It was true chotto had fallen down beside the
little mistress. But the Scarecrow and the Tin Woodman, not being made of flesh,
were not troubled by the scent of the flowers. “Run fast,” said the Scarecrow to
the Lion, “and get out of this deadly flowerbed as soon as you can. We will
bring the little girl with us, but if you should fall asleep you are too big to be
carried.” So the Lion aroused himself and bounded forward as fast as he could go.
In a moment he was out of sight. “Let us make a chair with our hands and carrier
said the Scarecrow. So they picked up Toto and put the dog in Dorothy’s lap,
and then they made a chair with their hands for the seat and their arms for
the arms and carried the little girl between them through the flowers. On and
on they walked, and it seemed that the great carpet of deadly flowers that
surrounded them would never end. They followed the bend of the river, and at
last came upon their friend the Lion, lying fast asleep among the poppies. The
flowers had been too strong for the huge beast and he had given up at last, and
fallen only a short distance from the end of the poppy bed, where the sweet
grass spread in beautiful green fields before them. “We can do nothing for him,”
said the Tin Woodman, sadly; “for he is much too heavy to lift.
We must leave him here to sleep on forever, and perhaps he will dream that
he has found courage at last.” “I’m sorry,” said the Scarecrow. “The Lion was a very
good comrade for one so cowardly. But let us go on.” They carried the sleeping girl
to a pretty spot beside the river, far enough from the poppy field to prevent
her breathing any more of the poison of the flowers, and here they laid her
gently on the soft grass and waited for the fresh breeze to awaken her end of Chapter 8